

# Faisal Ahmed

## **Software Engineer: MCSD-App Builder**

M: (571) 409-8514 | E: mishu dc@yahoo.com

## PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Full-stack software developer with 7+ years of experience in web development using **C#.net**, **Asp.net MVC**, **Asp.net Web API**, **Entity Framework**, **React** and **Angular**.

4+ years of experience in Web automation using Selenium WebDriver and Cucumber. Currently looking for a full-time position as a full-stack developer in a challenging environment to utilize my skill and knowledge to the best of my abilities and contribute positively to my personal growth as well as for the growth of the organization.

### SKILLS

- C#.net
- Asp.net MVC
- Asp.net Web API
- Entity Framework
- NHibernate
- jQuery
- React
- Angular

- Java
- Selenium WebDriver
- Cucumber
- Visual Studio
- Jira and Confluence
- Visual Studio Code
- Git

### **WORK HISTORY**

#### **QA ENGINEER**

01/2015 to CURRENT

#### DrFirst, Inc | Rockville, MD

- Projects: Electronic Prior Authorization, Patient Real Time Benefit Inquiry, Gaps in Care, Care Cost Estimator etc.
- Primary role is to automate web interfaces using Selenium WebDriver and Cucumber. API automation using Java, JMeter, Postman and verify user acceptance criteria.
- Worked in a React web portal as a software developer.
- Took the lead role in multiple UATs with Humana, Argus, United Health Group on behalf of DrFirst.
- Played the role of an acting application delivery manager for a short period of time.
- Participated in the myBenefitCheck project for Humana which was reported in Yahoo Finance in 2015

#### **SOFTWARE ENGINEER**

04/2011 to 09/2014

#### XpertLab BD Ltd. | Dhaka, Bangladesh

- Projects: E-Commerce System, Mobile-based Order Capturing System, Distribution Management System etc.
- Collaborated with developers, QA, product owner and scrum master to assess requirements, prioritized needs and produced high-quality products.
- Mobile-based Order Capturing System helped one renounced pharmaceutical company to double the number of invoices on month opening.
- Developed a Payroll Management System as a POC within a week to assist the sales team to provide a demo to a client.
- Troubleshoot production issues.
- Technology Used: C#.net, Asp.Net MVC, Web API, NHibernate, SQL Server.

12/2006 to 03/2010

#### **PROGRAMMER ANALYST**

### Computer Ease Ltd. | Dhaka, Bangladesh

- Projects: Humane Resource Management System, Payroll Management System, Distribution Management System.
- Participated in different steps of SDLC.
- Designed and developed application based on requirements using C#.net, Asp.Net, SQL Server, SOAP Services, J2ME.
- Migrated legacy Visual Basic project To C#.net.

#### **EDUCATION**

Master of Science | Computer Science United International University, Dhaka

2013

**Bachelor of Science** | Computer Science and Engineering Ahsanullah University of Science And Technology, Dhaka

2006

# CERTIFICATIONS & EXAMS

Exam 483: Programming in C#

Exam 486: Developing ASP.NET MVC Web Applications Exam 487: Developing Microsoft Azure and Web Services

## LINKS ()

Personal Profile: https://faisalahmed.us/

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/faisal-ahmed-se/

**Git**: https://github.com/mishu-dc

Leet Code: https://leetcode.com/mishu\_dc/